JITENDRA SONI

Store Manager with over 12 years of experience in developing a significant reputation for leadership due to excellent relationships with employees and willingness to lead by example.

House No. 356, Shyam Nagar Main, Near Electronic Complex, INDORE (M.P.) - 452010

Email: j.soni51@yahoo.co.in

Mob.: 9755017281



EXCEPTIONAL STORE OPERATIONS MANAGER

Accomplished operations management executive with extensive experience impacting organization presence, profitability, and performance through execution of high-impact sales, marketing and merchandising strategies. Dynamic leader with expertise in short/long-term strategic planning, operations planning, performance improvement, project management, and execution. Consistently exceed challenging organizational expectations across highly competitive markets.

	-								
AREA OF EXCELLENCE									
Sales Forecasting	F	Strategic Planning	F	Sales Management					
Communications Liaison		Succession Planning		Coaching/Motivating					
Operations Management		Inventory Management		Training/Development					
Budget/Financial Administration		Vendor Management		Performance Management					
LACT IOD DDOCUE.									
LAST JOB PROFILE :-									
Organization	ЦΩ	TEL EODTHNE LAND) K Indoro					

Organization	:	HOTEL FORTUNE LANDMARK, Indore
Designation	:	Purchase Officer

Duration : 02-11-2015 to 15-10-2017

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Organization : Hotel Mangal City, Indore
Designation : Purchase Cum Store Manager

Duration : 05-04-2013 to 05-10-2015

HOTEL RESPONSIBILITY

F Hotel Operation	F	Hospitality	F	Labour Scheduling
Food Safety	F	Stock Management	F	Health & Safety
© Cost Control		Up Selling		Spa Management
© Corporate Events		Licensing Laws		Staff Rules

Key Responsibilities:

• Food cost maintenance & stock maintain as per daily base work.

- ♦ Daily P.O., G.R.N., Issue as per daily base work (IDS 6i Software)
- ♦ Check & order daily base like :- Gas, Coal, Grocery, dairy products items, disposal, stationary & etc.
- Kitty Party, Marriage Party, Conference, Banquet- I, II, III, Kitchen, Housekeeping, Security, Car-Driver & etc. All type one person or department wise required any type material complete as per same requirement date.
- ♦ Hotel inventory report gives to M.D. Sir.
- Developed strategic corporate communications, sales and marketing plans, devised and executed key strategies for special events and campaigns. Planned and executed store opening and closings.
- Advised pyramid leadership across the organization on key issue, including marketing, finance, distribution centers, store planning loss prevention human resources field teams shortage results and top initiatives.
- Enhanced store inventory processes and increased vendor performance through improved
 Communication and follow-up.

Organization : <u>LIFE CARE HOSPITAL, Indore</u>

Designation : Store & Purchase Manager

Duration : 10-01-2010 to 05-03-2013

Key Responsibilities :-

- Daily O.T. Batch issue & Bill Entries, Material Issue, Q.C. Check.
- Daily Material issue to O.T., Club, Restaurants & Hospital All Counters.
- ♦ Monthly report for all type given to M.D.
- Daily Entry by manual register & software. (IN-OUT).
- Daily material Issue & Create & Given Purchase-Order for All Units.
 (CLUB, Hospital, Restaurants)
- Handling Hospital, Club & Restaurants Cash Counter.
- Monthly Board Meeting Attend.

Organization: NVIS Technology Pvt. Ltd., Indore

Designation : Store & Purchase Officer

Duration : 05-01-2005 to 01-01-2010

Key Responsibilities :-

- Daily Batch Issue & Bill Entries, Material Issue, Q.C. Check.
- ♦ 5000 Electric Items Arrange & Maintain per days and all working computerized (ERP Software-Use).

- ♦ 5000 Items Daily Issue & Received Use by ERP Software.
- Daily create & entered purchase order, misc register, job work register Job card, Bin card, M.R.R., G.C.R.N. Batch Plan, receipt, inspection and supervision doing all type store work as per daily base.
- Vendor calling for dues material.
- Stock maintain daily as per order booking.
- ◆ Dispatch material as per required order with bill, sticks, Challan, Form No. 49, 49-C, & Doing all dispatch work.

	ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION						
No.	Exam	Board/University	Year				
1.	B.Com. Plain	D.A.V.V. Indore	2003				
2.	Higher Secondary	M.P. Board Bhopal	2000				
3.	High School	M.P. Board Bhopal	1998				

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- ♦ 1 Year (A.D.C.S.) Advance Diploma in Computer Science from Classic Computer in Indore (M.P.)
- Training of E.R.P. & SAP Software From NVIS Technology, Industrial Area, Indore.
- Quick learner and ability meet deadlines.
- Competent in Microsoft Word, Excel, Access, Power Point, Windows and the Internet & Letter Drafting.
- Comprehensive knowledge of personnel training & development.
- Training of IDS 6i Software from Hotel Mangal City, Indore.

COMPUTER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- I have the knowledge and experience to operate E.R.P. & SAP software for 05 year in Nvis Technology, Industrial Area, Indore.
- I have the knowledge and experience to operate IDS 6i software for 02 years in Hotel Mangal City, Vijay Nagar, Indore

RESPONSIBILITY

I have handled purchase register, job work register, MISC Register, Job-Card, Bin-Card, M.R.R., G.C.R.N., Batch plan, receipt, inspection, and supervision on material handling, storage, material disbursement and disposal, inventory control, knowledge of E.R.P. & SAP & IDS 6i software, safety and security of store and housekeeping.

Maximized performance and profitability. Ensured stabilization of store systems through a team of nine exempt and four hourly associates. Met rigorous objective by focusing IT/vendors on software applications and supports of store systems technology. Led teams in testing and enhancements rollouts made at the corporate and field level.

AREA OF INTEREST

- Store & Purchase.
- Ware-House.
- Marketing.
- Computer & Admin Work.
- Drive all type vehicles.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name: : Mr. Rajendra Soni (Retired Person)

♦ Mother's Name : Mrs. Chanda Soni (House Wife)

♦ Wife's Name : Mrs. Ranu Soni (House Wife)

Daughter's Name : Baby Riddhi Soni (06 Years)

Nationality : Indian

❖ Caste (Category) : OBC

♦ Date of Birth : 15th December 1980

Languages Known : English & Hindi

♦ Marital Status : Married (11.02.2009)

♦ Hobbies : Listening Music, Internet Surfing, Car & Bike Driving

Strength: Hardworking, Dedication towards works, Punctual,

Co-operative.

DECLARATION

*	I hereby	declare	that	all	information	given	above	is	true	&	correct	to	the	best	of	my
	knowledg	ge.														

Date	:	

Place : INDORE [JITENDRA SONI]